Mohammad Arshad Hossain

Dhaka, Bangladesh 01871-273193 arshadhossaindhaka.bd@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Finance/Accounting professional with over 5 years of experience with different companies. I can contribute to maximizing productivity, profitability and competitiveness through my diverse skill sets. Distinguished for both technical & business acumen and ability to bridge gaps between technical, business and executive audiences. Earned degrees in both business & technology.

EDUCATION			
Master of Business Administration (MBA)	Specialization : Finance, MI	S Ashland University, USA	Dec, 2015
Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA)	Specialization : Finance	Independent University, BD	June, 2012
Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC)	Specialization : Business	Islamia Degree College	August, 2007
Secondary School Certificate (SSC)	Specialization : Business	Municipal Model High School	July, 2005

WORK EXPERIENCE

Account Receivable Specialist / Business Analyst

Jan 2019 – Dec 2021 Ohio, USA

EG America

- Performed various accounting tasks as assigned mostly in AR realms
- Worked on finding discrepancies in their financial documents
- Reconciled accounts in a timely manner.
- Prepared, examined and analyzed accounting records, financial statements, and other financial reports to assess accuracy.
- Created databases and wrote sql queries to fetch data from databases.
- Worked extensively with SMEs to prepare BRDs

Account Receivable Specialist Cintas

Nov 2017 – Dec 2018 Ohio, USA

 Performed general accounting tasks including Accounts Payable and Accounts Receivable.

- Worked on BillTrust and SAP extensively for cheque posting and credit analysis.
- Reconciled accounts in a timely manner.
- Prepared, examined and analyzed accounting records, financial statements, and other financial reports to assess accuracy.

Junior Accountant BABCO FOODS INTERNATIONAL LLC

Jan 2016- Oct 2017 NEW JERSEY, USA

- Posted customer payments by recording cash, checks, and credit card transactions in QuickBooks.
- Resolved collections by examining customer payment plans, payment history, credit line, coordinating contact with collections department.
- Resolved account discrepancies by obtaining and investigating information from sales, trade promotions, customer service departments, and from customers.
- Created sales report, collection report & area products report.
- Created invoices daily.

PROFESSIONAL DEGREE & CERTIFICATIONS

CompTia A+

CompTia Security+

Data Management

Data Structure & Algorithm